Live beyond fear.
Free Solo is a documentary, adventure film directed by Jimmy Chin.
Follow Alex Honnold as he attempts to become the first person to ever
free solo climb Yosemite's 3,000 foot high El Capitan wall.
With no ropes or safety gear, this would arguably be the
greatest feat in rock climbing history.
Self, played by Alex Honnold.
Self, played by Tommy Caldwell.
Self, played by Jimmy Chin.
Self, played by Sanni McCandless.
Self, played by Mikey Schaefer.
Self, played by Cheyne Lempe.
Free Solo is a 2018 American documentary film directed by Elizabeth Chai Vasarhelyi and Jimmy Chin that profiles rock climber Alex Honnold on his
quest to perform the first-ever free solo climb of a route on El Capitan, in Yosemite National Park in California, in June 2017.
The film premiered at the 45th Telluride Film Festival on August 31, 2018, and also screened at the 2018 Toronto
International Film Festival, where it won the People's Choice Award in the Documentaries category.
It was released in the United States on September 28, 2018, and
grossed over $28 million at the worldwide box office.
Free Solo received acclaim from critics and numerous accolades, including
winning Best Documentary Feature at the 91st Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of california, extreme sports,
mountain, yosemite, mountain climbing.